



My years of experience developing, presenting, and moving new products to customers as a Chemist led me to the world of Data Analysis. I hope to use my extensive analytical background along with garnered experience in my current Data Analytics Masters program to pivot into a Data Science role.

## **Education**

### **Georgia Institute of Technology**

M.S. IN DATA ANALYTICS

Expected graduation Aug. 2023

We Can Code IT

**CERTIFICATE OF SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT** 

**Marietta College** 

**B.S. IN BIOCHEMISTRY** 

Atlanta, Georgia

2021 - Present

Columbus, Ohio

2022

Marietta, Ohio 2003 - 2007

## **Skills**

**Languages:** Python, R, Hadoop, Spark, JavaScript, D3, Tableau, HTML, CSS, SASS, SQL, Java, GitBash, ARENA **Technical:** TDD, OOP, React, REST, Data Cleaning, Hyperparameter Tuning, Visualization, Imputation, Regression (Linear, Multiple, Poloynomial, Random Forest, SVR), Classification (KNN, SVM, Random Forest), Clustering (K-Means, Hierarchical), ANOVA, LASSO

# **Projects**

#### EXPLORATION AND VISUALIZATION OF LARGE-SCALE ONLINE VIDEO UPLOADS METADATA

2022

This collaborative project, inspired by the "Butterfly Effect" podcast, sought to visualize trends of user-generated tags on videos hosted by a major video website. User-generated communities and their evolution over time was visualized.

- 3-million video URLs scraped from online corpus utilizing scrapy python library subsequently cleaned and transformed for analysis.
- · Anomaly detection via angle-based-outlier allowed easy comparison of anomalous tags, top 50 anomolies visualized.
- · Community detection and visualization using user-generated tags using both Leiden and Louvain clustering algorithms.
- Visualizations presented in both RMD utilizing R, and D3 via AWS server.

#### **OIL TANKER SIMULATION AND OPTIMIZATION**

2022

Inspired by the notorious "Ever Given" debacle which caused massive supply chain issues around the world. ARENA simulation software was used to quantify and optimize ship de/berthing, un/loading, and travel times utilizing a single tug traveling to and from berths to harbor.

#### PREDICTING NFL DRAFT SELECTION USING NFL COMBINE DATA

2021

Using available NFL Combine data and NFL Draft Selection data drew insights on which measured attributes contributed to draft pick status for NFL prospects.

- Deep cleaning and pruning, MICE imputation of joined data with respect ot preventing bias.
- Variable selection using LASSO allowed for classification of individuals with specific attributes into different position rankings.

# **Work Experience**

### **ASK Chemicals LP**

Dublin, Ohio

2016 - Mar. 2022

#### RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT CHEMIST

- Implemented data dashboard to track plant manufacturing defects in contrast with past performances, optimizing a previously entirely manual process, utilizing R, R-Shiny, Excel, CentOS VM.
- Performed cost analysis on industry specialty products, involved testing of new chemical compositions and optimization of formulations, utilized design of experiments and statistical comparisons in MATLAB and R software.
- Developed advanced Excel templates to aid in laboratory requests, progress, and results. Further implemented into MS Access database to allow for tracking and advanced analysis.
- · Advanced 3D-printing manufacturing process using RFID, Proxmark tools, resulting in \$5MM USD realized cost savings.
- Consistently employed Six Sigma methodology, experimental design, statistically rigorous analysis.

PRODUCT SPECIALIST 2014 - 2016

- Constructed and administered MS Access database for inventory control and safety data sheet management. Conformed to OSHA standards for hazardous chemicals control.
- Developed a method of high-throughput, automated time series analysis using R, reducing technician processing times from 10 minutes to 10 seconds.